# jim Rothstein

```
jimrothstein@gmail.com
(831) 824-4304 (messages)
```

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jimrothstein

https://github.com/jimrothstein

# Clinical Trials Package Developer (R)

### Overview

R package developer. Worked with pharmaverse, including admiral, and pilot5 JSON delivery to FDA. Worked with CDISC standards, such a ADaM, SDTM, and including schema and REST api. Seek to focus on Clinical Trials R package development.

### Related Skills

- R, 4+ years
- tidyverse, httr2, data.table, shiny, quarto ...
- SQL: 2+ years, joins, dplyr
- Rstudio, emacs, neovim
- admiral, admiraldev, sdtmchecks
- github
- zsh shell
- linux

### Recent Projects & Skills

- (active) Fix issues in Pharamaverse Admiral and sdmtchecks R packages. Attend developer meetings. Wrote github actions workflow to automate.
- (active) Using Shiny developed preliminary dashboard for analysis of Drug Benefit Denials (public data from Center for Medicare and Medicaid (CMS)).
- (active) Used youtube API and httr and httr2 to add/modify youtube.com playlists. Used OAUTH tokens scope. Active participant developing book Web APIs with R, using openAPI framework.
- Used tools in rrapply, tidyr, vctrs, tibblify to unravel deeply nested JSONs in tree/json format to table (from REST apis)

• (active) Contribute to various Open Source projects (Github)

# **RELATED WORK HISTORY:**

2014 - present **R-Coders** Self-employed R programmer.

1996-2014 Self-employed contractor, including

- Webmaster, community expatriate website in China, 2005 2008 Setup, maintain, promote expat community-based website in Dalian, China. Selected Joomla, hosting company, hired and trained student volunteers.
- Capital IT Group, Dalian, China 2004- Mentor Chinese software engineers, light project management, pre and post sales.
- Center for Electronic Art, San Francisco, 2002 Taught Java, mySQL, jsp classes. Also supervised graduate student modeling shipping/ordering/inventory system.
- Teaching (1998-2012) Taught classes java, math, internet, statistics in China and California community college in US. Certified to teach math in at California community college.

Webmaster, Saratoga Systems, Campbell, CA (1996-1998) Maintain NT and IIS server. Various internet projects.

Web Database Development, Microsoft, Redmond, WA (1996) Web database applications using Asp, MS SQL; contractor.

Contract Programming Assignments: Chicago, IL (1986-1996) Designed and developed variety of business database applications (Paradox, Delphi, Access) For example

- Developed relational database model for insurance company to track debt and assets of its multi-billion dollar joint ventures/commercial properties.
- Developed order tracking system (paradox).
- Contributed to bank risk management tool (ms access)

#### **Education**

BS MIT, physics

Jim Rothstein – jimrothstein@gmail.com – (831) 824-4304